https://github.com/probinso

Personal Statement

I have 7+ years experience, solving increasingly difficult problems with software. My diverse work history spans both products and research, including data pipelines/management, medical informatics, programming languages, and computer securities. My graduate studies focused on applications of machine learning in audio, image, and text processing. I have developed strong interests in data analysis/exploration, information retrieval, data engineering, and machine learning.

Persistent Experience :

C, C++ Pvthon Linux TDD

R, dplyr $\mathbb{E}T_{\mathbf{F}}X$ Git Ticketing Systems

Work Experience _

- Machine Learning in Marine Acoustics (continuing) Graduate Research with ACO

Researched deep unsupervised anomaly detectors, for sane indexing of 10 year audio track Developed ACOio, an intuitive ACO track explorer, to rejuvenate data access for researchers Developed principled audio processing and noise-suppression, focused on marine bioacoustics

Technologies: Python, ACOio, tensorflow, scipy.signal, Jupyter

HappyWhale

- Staff Engineer

March 2019 - present

Thinkful (Part Time) - Data Science Technical Expert Jan. 2019 - present Advised career transitioners in mastery of professional and data science topics

Provided safe environment for training and instruction in a remote-first setting

- Graduate Data Science Intern June 2018 - Sept. 2018 NASA Jet Propulsion Lab Fully specified programmatic solution from use-case meetings with top NASA/JPL employees Designed & developed Expert Modeling/Recommender System, by extending the Author-Topic-Model Implemented stable/principled text normalization, tokenization, and model evaluation Open Source contributions to the gensim's natural language processing library

Technologies: Python, nltk, gensim, pyLDAvis, pandas, Jupyter

- Research Assistant OHSU Fair Neuroimaging Lab Oct. 2017 - June 2018

Contributed to microbiome population analytics tools, to study female reproductive system Developed processing pipeline and audit tools for reported data and FMRI, on AHDH/ASD studies Acted as standards and Open Source release lead, developing and enforcing best practices

Technologies: Python, Bash, R, neo4j, ponyorm, stan, GitLab, Docker

RGB Optics (Part Time) - Contractor Nov. 2015 - Aug. 2018

Developed custom photo image processing tools for low cost spectral profile analysis Authored educational material in light pollution's effect on economy, biology, and technology Provided live technology tutorials and consulting on optimization and image processing

Technologies: Python, numpy, skimage, R, AWS, PostgreSQL, Perl, C++, Jira, ZenHub

- Research Engineer April 2014 - Dec 2015 Galois Inc.

Contributed to PPAML, Overseas Voting Foundation, Safeware, Robot Fast Track Developed processing pipelines and workflows to enable evaluator work for DARPA programs Produced biannual quantitative and qualitative reports on for DARPA and language developers

Technologies: Python, SLURM, Scala, Figaro, Chimpy, Docker, Jira, Basecamp

EMC² Isilon Storage - Software Development Engineer Dec. 2012 - July 2013

Designed and developed password manager to supporting self encrypting drives in FreeBSD Brought to schedule a lagging anchor release feature in approximately 5 months Participated in threat modeling for multiple security sensitive applications

Technologies: C, C++, Python, SQLite, Subversion, FreeBSD, OpenSSL

Neato Projects

Multiple Myeloma Clinical Trials, custom named-entity boosted topic model numpy, Python Topic modeling and applications, a presentation for non-statisticians beamer, MTEX Workshop collaborative introduction to GitHub and slides markdown, bash, github.api Morphological Watersheding Algorithms pyspark, numpy, ndimage, Python Relevance Vector Machine Information Retrieval Cluster/Rank Demo Harness flask, numpy, nltk, sklearn, Python Gene Data Breast Cancer Drug Predictor R, caret Distributed Fully Homomorphic Encryption System Hadoop, Sagemath Concurrent Elliptic Curve Cryptography Module Sagemath, Erlang Multilingual Analysis of Subordinating and Coordinating Conjunctions R, Perl AdaRailz Concurrent Model Train Control System Ada

Education

Oregon Health Science University

CSLU

Computer Science MSc 2016 - present

Courses

* Advanced Topics in Machine Learning
Deep Learning
Machine Learning
Artificial Intelligence
Statistical Methods
Univariate Statistical Analysis
Analysis of Sequences

Western Washington University

Computer Science BS, Mathematics Minor June 2012

Electives :

Homomorphic Encryption Systems Cryptography & Elliptic Curves Artificial Intelligence Natural Language Processing Functional Programming Computer Graphics

- * Natural Language Processing
- * Advanced Topics in Signal Processing Speech Signal Processing Problem Solving with Large Clusters Image Processing Information Retrieval Computing Ethics

Computer Science

Computer Architecture
Number Theory
Elementary Real Analysis
Abstract Algebra
Linear Algebra I/II
Ordinary Differential Equations